<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//XMLmind//DTD BoostBook//EN"
"http://www.boost.org/tools/boostbook/dtd/boostbook.dtd">
<section>
  <title>Raster</title>

  <section>
    <title>Summary</title>

    <para>The Moving Window library works with data that conforms to the
    Raster Concept. Geographical raster layers carry information of the
    spatial distribution of some variable. The data is stored in a matrix that
    corresponds to a regular grid and where the each cell, or pixel,
    corresponds to a square square geograpical area. To convert from matrix
    indices to geographical coordinates it is necessary to know the
    orientation of the grid, its corner coordinates and the size of each cell.
    The moving window library is not concerned with aspects of geographical
    representation, but only considers the matrix of pixel values.</para>

    <para>Thus a Raster is not more than a matrix. The operation on Raster
    that are supported are to query the dimension of the matrix and to access
    values. </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Valid Expressions</title>

    <table>
      <title>Valid expression</title>

      <tgroup cols="3">
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry>Expression</entry>

            <entry>Effect</entry>

            <entry>Default (moving_windows/raster_traits.h)</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>blink::raster::raster_traits::value_type:value_type&lt;R&gt;</entry>

            <entry>the value type of raster elements</entry>

            <entry>R::value_type</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>blink::raster::raster_traits::coordinate_type&lt;R&gt;</entry>

            <entry>the type used to give raster coordinate pairs, must conform
            to the Coordinate concept (not documented)</entry>

            <entry>R::coordinate_type</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>blink::raster::raster_traits::index_type&lt;R&gt;</entry>

            <entry>the type used give individual raster coordinates, must be
            an integer type</entry>

            <entry>R::index_type</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>blink::raster::raster_traits::iterator&lt;R&gt;</entry>

            <entry>iterator type for the raster for the raster.</entry>

            <entry>R::iterator</entry>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>auto i = r.begin();</entry>

            <entry>return the iterator at the first element.</entry>

            <entry/>
          </row>

          <row>
            <entry>auto rows = blink::raster::raster_operations::size1(r);</entry>

            <entry>returns the number of rows in the raster.</entry>

            <entry/>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>auto cols = blink::raster::raster_operations::size2(r);</entry>

            <entry>returns the number of columns in the raster.</entry>

            <entry/>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>

    <para/>
  </section>
</section>
